<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections on EDUC5464 ICT Curriculum 1</title>
    <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflections on EDUC5464 ICT Curriculum 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/coding/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;coding-as-a-literacy&#34;&gt;Coding as a Literacy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;NMC/CoSN Horizon Report: 2016 K-12&lt;/em&gt; Becker, Freeman, Giessinger Hall, Cummins and Yuhnke (2016) report that coding, or computer programming, is increasingly being adopted in school curriculums around the world in response to economic factors and the belief that coding can assist with the development of a raft of fluencies that are often described using the term &amp;lsquo;21st century skills&amp;rsquo;.  Becker et al (2016) see this trend increasing into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Australia factors such as our falling PISA ranking and the desire to transition our economy from its reliance on resources spurred moves towards creating an innovation mindset and a STEM focus in schools.  Consequently coding is an integral part of the new Digital Technologies curriculum currently being introduced in Australian schools (!ACARA ref!).  Additionally, within Western Australia the recently elected Premier Mark McGowan has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markmcgowan.com.au/news/science-and-coding-in-schools-to-create-jobs-for-the-future-1303&#34;&gt;pledged $2 million dollars&lt;/a&gt; to fund the integration of coding into the school curriculum.  In short, coding has already arrived in the Western Australian education system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a pre-service ICT teacher who desires to teach coding this is an issue close to my heart.  I agree that coding can help develop 21st century skills but I believe it can be greatly beneficial to traditional skills as well and offers great possibilities when combined with other curriculum areas, particularly maths and science.  As far back as 1980 Seymour Papert wrote his seminal book Mindstorms where he argued for computers to be used as learning tools for children to become &amp;ldquo;builders of their own intellectual structures&amp;rdquo; (Papert, 1980).  Unfortunately, over time computer usage in schools evolved to something more mundane, far removed from what was imagined by Papert.  Coding in the curriculum may help unlock the true potential of computers for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m extremely dubious about the economic claims made around coding.  For example, Becker et al (2016) quote a prediction made by code.org that by 2020 there will be 1,000,000 more computing jobs than computing graduates (presumably in the US).  This sounds impressive but code.org provide no evidence for how the statistic was calculated nor do they explain what a computing job is.  One problem with statistics around ICT employment is that they often conflate a wide range of jobs such as sales, support and facilities management with software development.  Additionally, there is evidence that the supposed talent shortage within America is actually a ploy to get approval to employ cheap foreign labour on H1-B visas, for example Weismann (2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst the introduction of coding into schools is exciting and offers many great possibilities we need to be clear on why we are doing it.  We are inevitably lead to the question of what is the purpose of education.  Is the role of schools to train students for future jobs?  If this is the reason for the introduction of coding then we need to be honest and realistic about future job prospects but hopefully coding in the curriculum can be justified on more than purely economic grounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adams Becker, S., Freeman, A., Giesinger Hall, C., Cummins, M.,
and Yuhnke, B. (2016). &lt;em&gt;NMC/CoSN Horizon Report: 2016 K-12
Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Austin, Texas: The New Media Consortium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Papert, S. (1980). &lt;em&gt;Mindstorms: Children, computers, and powerful ideas&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, Inc..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weissmann, J. (2013). &lt;em&gt;The myth of America&amp;rsquo;s tech talent shortage&lt;/em&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2013/04/the-myth-of-americas-tech-talent-shortage/275319/&#34;&gt;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2013/04/the-myth-of-americas-tech-talent-shortage/275319/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing
Testing
One
Two
Three&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>