<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections on EDUC5464 ICT Curriculum 1</title>
    <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflections on EDUC5464 ICT Curriculum 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/coding/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;coding-as-a-literacy&#34;&gt;Coding as a Literacy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;NMC/CoSN Horizon Report: 2016 K-12&lt;/em&gt; Becker, Freeman, Giessinger Hall, Cummins and Yuhnke (2016) report that coding, or computer programming, is increasingly being adopted in school curriculums around the world in response to economic factors and the belief that coding can assist with the development of a raft of fluencies that are often described using the term &amp;lsquo;21st century skills&amp;rsquo;.  Becker et al (2016) see this trend increasing into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Australia factors such as our falling PISA ranking and the desire to transition our economy from its reliance on resources spurred moves towards creating an innovation mindset and a STEM focus in schools.  Consequently coding is an integral part of the new Digital Technologies curriculum currently being introduced in Australian schools (ACARA, 2017).  Additionally, within Western Australia the recently elected Premier Mark McGowan has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markmcgowan.com.au/news/science-and-coding-in-schools-to-create-jobs-for-the-future-1303&#34;&gt;pledged $2 million dollars&lt;/a&gt; to fund the integration of coding into the school curriculum.  In short, coding has already arrived in the Western Australian education system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a pre-service ICT teacher who desires to teach coding this is an issue close to my heart.  I agree that coding can help develop 21st century skills but I believe it can be greatly beneficial to traditional skills as well and offers great possibilities when combined with other curriculum areas, particularly maths and science.  As far back as 1980 Seymour Papert wrote his seminal book Mindstorms where he argued for computers to be used as learning tools for children to become &amp;ldquo;builders of their own intellectual structures&amp;rdquo; (Papert, 1980).  Unfortunately, over time computer usage in schools evolved to something more mundane, far removed from what was imagined by Papert.  Coding in the curriculum may help unlock the true potential of computers for learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I&amp;rsquo;m extremely dubious about the economic claims made around coding.  For example, Becker et al (2016) quote a prediction made by code.org that by 2020 there will be 1,000,000 more computing jobs than computing graduates (presumably in the US).  This sounds impressive but code.org provide no evidence for how the statistic was calculated nor do they explain what a computing job is.  One problem with statistics around ICT employment is that they often conflate a wide range of jobs such as sales, support and facilities management with software development.  If job prospects are the main driver for teaching coding then we need to be honest about what those job prospects are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must also consider the ability of schools to move in this direction.  I feel secondary schools, particularly large ones that already have specialist staff teaching subjects such as Computer Science will easily move towards coding as a literacy and, in fact, many of them are already on this path.  Where I see trouble arising is in primary schools where it often falls on the class teacher to teach all aspects of the curriculum.  There are, no doubt, many primary teachers capable of teaching coding but I have also encountered many reluctant ones and some may feel teaching coding wasn&amp;rsquo;t the job they signed up for.  Fortunately, the coding curriculum for primary school is fairly trivial and as long as students emerge from primary school with a positive disposition towards ICT and coding then any shortfall in their knowledge can easily be corrected in secondary school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACARA. (2017). Digital Technologies.    Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.australiancurriculum.edu.au/technologies/digital-technologies/curriculum/f-10?layout=1&#34;&gt;http://www.australiancurriculum.edu.au/technologies/digital-technologies/curriculum/f-10?layout=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adams Becker, S., Freeman, A., Giesinger Hall, C., Cummins, M.,
and Yuhnke, B. (2016). &lt;em&gt;NMC/CoSN Horizon Report: 2016 K-12
Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Austin, Texas: The New Media Consortium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Papert, S. (1980). &lt;em&gt;Mindstorms: Children, computers, and powerful ideas&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, Inc..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/create_or_consume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/create_or_consume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ict-for-consumption-vs-creation&#34;&gt;ICT for Consumption Vs Creation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 Australian Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull gave a speech entitled The Importance of Tech Education in Our Schools (Turnbull, 2014).  In his speech Turnbull (2014) argued that in our modern times even young children had ICT capabilities, such as using an iPad, and the focus of education should move to teaching children to be creators rather than passive consumers of digital technologies.  Turnbull (2014) was largely paraphrasing the thoughts of US President Barack Obama who had admonished American students to “Don’t just play on your phone, program it’” Turnbull (2014).  Now, in 2017, we find Malcolm Turnbull’s sentiments encoded in the Australian Digital Technologies Curriculum which seeks to enable students to “become innovative creators of digital solutions” (ACARA, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm Turnbull was explicit in his view that a move to teaching students to become digital creators was driven by an economic imperative, specifically that jobs of the future will require these skills (Turnbull, 2014).  There is also the view that there are many technologies such as robotics, AI and 3d printing that are on the cusp of explosive growth and governments around the world desire to share in the economic benefits (Dougherty, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to see this move towards an emphasis on digital creation, especially as I want to teach coding and my educational philosophy is aligned with constructivism and an emphasis on “learning by doing”.  However, I share the view of Blikstein and Worsley (2016) that we must be careful to emphasise the process of creation over the product of creation.  Blikstein (2013) coined the phrase “keychain syndrome” to describe a phenomenon he witnessed whereby students in a class were introduced to digital fabrication technologies with a simple keychain exercise, however, the students never wanted to progress beyond making the keychains as they received a massive return on their minimal time investment as people unfamiliar with the fabrication technology were amazed by their creations.  Keychain syndrome has since been adopted as a term to describe trivialised projects that are designed to be produced within tight time constraints but impress people unfamiliar with the technology involved (Martinez &amp;amp; Stager, 2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel we must be careful in Australian schools to not overemphasise product over process.  Students need to be able to undertake meaningful, complex projects that can potentially fail so they can learn valuable skills such as creativity, innovation, persistence and problem solving.  To conclude, I would like to offer the example of &lt;a href=&#34;http://codecamp.com.au/&#34;&gt;Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; as an example of where Australian schools should not head.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://codecamp.com.au/&#34;&gt;Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; offers after school and school holiday programs that “teach kids to code”.  They utilise creator vs consumer rhetoric in their advertising and there is a heavy emphasis on the fact that children will have produced a working game at the end of their course.  To achieve such a goal the students are heavily scaffolded and guided down certain paths, there is little opportunity for divergent thinking.  I believe &lt;a href=&#34;http://codecamp.com.au/&#34;&gt;Code Camp&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent example of keychain syndrome in action.  In contrast, &lt;a href=&#34;http://coderdojowa.org.au/&#34;&gt;CoderDojo&lt;/a&gt; provides extra-curricular coding clubs but children choose their own project and are largely self-guided and I feel this is a better model for schools to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACARA. (2017). Digital Technologies.    &lt;a href=&#34;Retrieved from http://www.australiancurriculum.edu.au/technologies/digital-technologies/curriculum/f-10?layout=1&#34;&gt;Retrieved from http://www.australiancurriculum.edu.au/technologies/digital-technologies/curriculum/f-10?layout=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blikstein, P. (2013). Digital fabrication and ‘making’in education: The democratization of invention. &lt;em&gt;FabLabs: Of machines, makers and inventors&lt;/em&gt;, 1-21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blikstein, P., &amp;amp; Worsley, M. (2016). Children Are Not Hackers: Building a Culture of Powerful Ideas, Deep Learning and Equity in the Maker Movement. &lt;em&gt;Makeology: Makerspaces as learning environments&lt;/em&gt;, 1, 64.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dougherty, D. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Free to Make: How the Maker Movement is Changing Our Schools, Our Jobs and Our Minds&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, California: North Atlantic Books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martinez, S. L., &amp;amp; Stager, G. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Invent to learn: Making, tinkering, and engineering in the classroom&lt;/em&gt;. Constructing modern knowledge press Torrance, CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turnbull, M. (2014). Speech: The Importance of Tech Education in Our Schools.    Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.malcolmturnbull.com.au/media/speech-the-importance-of-tech-education-in-our-schools&#34;&gt;https://www.malcolmturnbull.com.au/media/speech-the-importance-of-tech-education-in-our-schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/reflections/games/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;video-game-development-for-learning&#34;&gt;Video Game Development for Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing video games was my entry point into the world of computer programming and I have many fond high school memories of spending time in the computer lab with my friends developing and playing our games.  We never felt like we were learning but with hindsight informed by studying teaching I see we were immersed in a social constructivist learning experience that many teachers would love to be able to orchestrate for their students.  My high school programming career was played out against the back drop of the golden age of arcade video games and needless to say video games and the surrounding culture was a large preoccupation for myself and my friends.  Again, with hindsight, I see how my engagement and motivation to program computer games was driven by my interest in playing video games outside of school.  Developing video games in high school was such a profound and enjoyable experience for me that I want to provide that experience for my students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our present day video games are still a major preoccupation for adolescents.  Granic, Lobel, and Engels (2014) report 91% of children aged between 2 and 17 in the United States play video games.  This staggering statistic is partly driven by mobile devices with every mobile phone now capable of playing games that would have astounded my high school self.  Even without mobile gaming the world of video games is an important facet of teenage culture.  The Australian Professional Standards for Teachers impels teachers to “Know students” (AITSL, 2012) and it could be argued that understanding important elements of teenage culture such as video games and music is essential to understanding teenage students.  The standards also task teachers with delivering engaging lessons (AITSL, 2012) and it is well accepted that lessons tied to students’ interests that connect meaningfully to their lives will increase student engagement (McDonald, 2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With computer programming, or coding, now a part of the Australian curriculum (ACARA, 2017) developing video games provides a wonderful opportunity to teach students this skill in a way that is engaging to them.  Papert (1998) also saw engaging students in video game development as a powerful means to teach them coding skills but more importantly as a basis for teaching them about learning.  Papert (1998) envisaged a future where children would develop video games as readily as they draw pictures or write stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video game development also provides a great opportunity to reinforce math concepts.  A common complaint of high school mathematics students is that they can see no use for the concepts they are learning (Ellenberg, 2015).  However, many mathematics concepts can be directly applied in video games, particularly for 3d games.  For example, many people struggle to see the point of complex numbers (a number that includes an imaginary component that is the seemingly impossible square root of a negative number), however, complex numbers form the basis of quaternions which are widely used for describing rotations in 3d games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon my first day of practicum as a pre-service teacher I was given my mentor’s timetable and was greatly pleased to see Game Design classes peppered throughout the week.  I have only attended one Game Design class to date but I was overjoyed to see a class of students deeply engaged in creating games and enthusiastically demonstrating their creations to me.  I recently learnt about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stemgames.org.au/&#34;&gt;Australian STEM Video Game Challenge&lt;/a&gt; which is a competition sponsored by ACER and encourages students to create and submit video games to the competition (Australian STEM Video Game Challenge, 2017) and will be encouraging my students to enter.  I now feel my dream to teach students video game development is within reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACARA. (2017). Digital Technologies.    Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.australiancurriculum.edu.au/technologies/digital-technologies/curriculum/f-10?layout=1&#34;&gt;http://www.australiancurriculum.edu.au/technologies/digital-technologies/curriculum/f-10?layout=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AITSL. (2012). Australian Professional Standards for Teachers. Victoria: Author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australian STEM Video Game Challenge. (2017). Our Mission.    Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stemgames.org.au/about/our-mission&#34;&gt;https://www.stemgames.org.au/about/our-mission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellenberg, J. (2015). &lt;em&gt;How not to be wrong: The power of mathematical thinking&lt;/em&gt;. Penguin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granic, I., Lobel, A., &amp;amp; Engels, R. C. (2014). The benefits of playing video games. &lt;em&gt;American Psychologist&lt;/em&gt;, 69(1), 66.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McDonald, T. (2013). &lt;em&gt;Classroom management: Engaging students in learning&lt;/em&gt;. Melbourne: Oxford University Press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Papert, S. (1998). Does easy do it? Children, games, and learning. &lt;em&gt;Game developer magazine&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>