<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on EDUC5464 ICT Curriculum 1</title>
    <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on EDUC5464 ICT Curriculum 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;

  {{ partial &#34;head.html&#34; . }}

  &lt;body&gt;

    {{ partial &#34;nav.html&#34; . }}
&lt;!--
    &lt;header class=&#34;header-section &#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;intro-header no-img&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;col-lg-8 col-lg-offset-2 col-md-10 col-md-offset-1&#34;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;page-heading&#34;&gt;
                       
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/header&gt;
--&gt;   
	&lt;script src=&#34;//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/p5.js/0.5.9/p5.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
	&lt;script src=&#34;../../doc/sketch.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;div id=&#34;wrap&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;section id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;avatar&#34;&gt;
          &lt;img class=&#34;img-circle&#34; src=&#34;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}img/{{ .Site.Params.avatar }}&#34; alt=&#34;Responsive image&#34; width=&#34;75&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;width:50%;text-align:justify&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m &lt;strong&gt;{{ .Site.Author.name }}&lt;/strong&gt;, a pre-service teacher studying at UWA.  This is my website for the unit &lt;a href=&#34;http://handbooks.uwa.edu.au/units/unitdetails?code=EDUC5464&#34;&gt; ICT Curriculum 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Please read some of my &lt;a href=&#34;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}page/reflections/&#34;&gt; reflections&lt;/a&gt; on topics related to ICT and education, have a look at some &lt;a href=&#34;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}page/tools/&#34;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; that can be useful for teaching
        or view my assessment &lt;a href=&#34;{{ .Site.BaseURL }}page/resources/&#34;&gt; resources&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/section&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


    {{ partial &#34;footer.html&#34; . }}

  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/minecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/minecraft/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;minecraft&#34;&gt;Minecraft&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/p5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/p5/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;p5-js&#34;&gt;p5.js&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/p5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://p5js.org/&#34;&gt;p5.js&lt;/a&gt; is a JavaScript library that aims to make creative coding accessible to artists, designers, educators and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros&#34;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web browser based so it runs on many platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses JavaScript which is an industry standard programming language with a lot of learning materials and support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified framework limits scope of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No standard development environment so some time must be spent investigating tools and setting up a development environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-for&#34;&gt;Recommended For&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A great next step for students that are pushing the boundaries of what is possible in Scratch or other visual programming tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year 8, 9 and 10 programming classes as a first introduction to a general purpose programming language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing interactive teaching resources for maths, science and ICT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p5.js is part of the Processing family that aims to make creative coding accessible to artists, designers, educators and students.  p5.js has the additional goal of providing an environment that runs in modern web browsers with no additional requirements.  The concept of creative coding is somewhat nebulous but generally covers artistic endeavours that may or may not be interactive and often process images, sounds and video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p5.js is a great introduction to what the Australian Digital Technologies Curriculum describes as a general purpose programming language.  p5.js uses the JavaScript language which is an industry standard programming language that is part of the glue (along with HTML and CSS) that enables interactive web sites.  Whilst students will be introduced to JavaScript p5.js deliberately limits the scope to reduce the cognitive load.  Students can produce engaging, interactive programs with only a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p5.js is free and open source.  As it is browser based it will run on any device that can run modern JavaScript including iPads and netbooks.  For development all that is required is a text editor, however, it would be recommended to introduce students to an integrated development environment that provides scaffolding such as syntax highlighting and code completion.  A great option is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Visual Studio Code which is free and runs on Mac OS X and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the downside, the type of project that can be developed with p5.js is limited.  For example, although games can be developed it is not recommended.  However, once students want to move to the next level they can easily transport their JavaScript to other frameworks such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://phaser.io/&#34;&gt;Phaser&lt;/a&gt; which is an HTML5 game framework that uses JavaScript as its programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an example of what can be done using p5.js.  The example is taken from the openprocessing website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.openprocessing.org/sketch/152169/embed/&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/scratch/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;scratch&#34;&gt;Scratch&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/scratch.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scratch.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;Scratch&lt;/a&gt; is a visual programming tool that is targeted at beginning programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros&#34;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web and desktop versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online community with over 1 million shared projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web version requires Flash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screen size of projects is limited to 480x360 pixels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More complex projects require convoluted work arounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-for&#34;&gt;Recommended For&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to programming for primary school, Year 7 and Year 8 students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scratch is a visual programming tool that was developed by the Lifelong Kindergarten Group which is part of the MIT Media Lab.  It can be seen as a spiritual successor to the Logo programming language that was developer by Seymour Papert to teach programming concepts to children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scratch is a fantastic entry point to introduce students to programming and it is widely used in schools and extra curricular programs such as CoderDojo.  Students can create a myriad of interactive projects such as games, animations, interactive movies and electronic cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scratch has a web based interface that requires Flash to run as well as a desktop version that can run on Mac OS X and Windows.  It does not require a lot of resources and will run comfortably on older hardware and limited devices such a netbooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big advantage of Scratch is the online community that has grown up around it.  Scratch community members are encouraged to share their projects and remix other people&amp;rsquo;s projects.  In addition to sharing projects Scratch community members participate in online forums and it is a great introduction to online collaboration and communities for children.  The community is well moderated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the downside Scratch is showing its age, it has just recently celebrated its 10th anniversary.  This is most apparent in its dependence upon Flash which has slowly been falling from favour as web sites move away from reliance on browser plugins mainly due to security concerns.  The screen size of 480x360 seems antiquated in today&amp;rsquo;s widescreen high definition world.  However, Scratch 3.0 is in the works and promises a modernised version based on HTML 5 technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developers of Scratch have put considerable thought into keeping it simple but, unfortunately, this can cause limitations once students want to undertake more ambitious projects.  Often complex Scratch projects will have to resort to workarounds and poor practices to bypass limitations.  Once students get to the point that they are &amp;ldquo;fighting&amp;rdquo; with the limitations of Scratch I would recommend they move to a new environment such as p5.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-bugs&#34;&gt;Example - &amp;ldquo;Bugs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an example of what can be done in Scratch, click on the green flag to run.  Note that you will require Flash support to be enabled in your browser to run the example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;485&#34; height=&#34;402&#34; src=&#34;//scratch.mit.edu/projects/embed/112550184/?autostart=false&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>18819519@student.uwa.edu.au (Stephen Oldmeadow)</author>
      <guid>https://soldmeadow.github.io/educ5464/tools/unity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;unity&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../img/unity.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unity3d.com/&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt; is a cross-platform game engine and integrated development environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros&#34;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free for not for profit and education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry standard used on many famous games such as Angry Birds 2 and Kerbal Space Program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong support and active user community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many paths for differentiated learning as projects can be created with no coding but at the other end the scope for complexity is unlimited and students could build a production ready game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning curve can be steep, particularly for the teacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires moderately capable hardware to run the IDE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although Unity is free there are add-ons for purchase.  Whilst add-ons are not necessary there are situations where they are highly recommended and would save a lot of time.  It would be prudent to budget for at least some expenditure on add-ons.  The price is often low ($10-$20) with very few add-ons exceeding $100.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-for&#34;&gt;Recommended For&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students with an interest in game development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year 9 and 10 advanced programming classes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year 11 and 12 students in vocational ICT streams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to 3D graphics concepts and 3D maths concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of interactive teaching tools that utilise 3D graphics including virtual-reality and augmented-reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p5.js is part of the Processing family that aims to make creative coding accessible to artists, designers, educators and students.  p5.js has the additional goal of providing an environment that runs in modern web browsers with no additional requirements.  The concept of creative coding is somewhat nebulous but generally covers artistic endeavours that may or may not be interactive and often process images, sounds and video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p5.js is a great introduction to what the Australian Digital Technologies Curriculum describes as a general purpose programming language.  p5.js uses the JavaScript language which is an industry standard programming language that is part of the glue (along with HTML and CSS) that enables interactive web sites.  Whilst students will be introduced to JavaScript p5.js deliberately limits the scope to reduce the cognitive load.  Students can produce engaging, interactive programs with only a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p5.js is free and open source.  As it is browser based it will run on any device that can run modern JavaScript including iPads and netbooks.  For development all that is required is a text editor, however, it would be recommended to introduce students to an Integrated Development Environment that provides scaffolding such as syntax highlighting and code completion.  A great option is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Visual Studio Code which is free and runs on Mac OS X and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the downside, the type of project that can be developed with p5.js is limited.  For example, although games can be developed it is not recommended.  However, once students want to move to the next level they can easily transport their JavaScript to other frameworks such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://phaser.io/&#34;&gt;Phaser&lt;/a&gt; which is an HTML5 game framework that uses JavaScript as its programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an example of what can be done using Unity.  The example is taken from &lt;a href=&#34;http://dustyroom.com/colr/demo/&#34;&gt;http://dustyroom.com/colr/demo/&lt;/a&gt;.  Note that you will require a web browser with support for WebGL to view the demo (Chrome is fine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;640&#34; src=&#34;//dustyroom.com/colr/demo/&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>